# **KOJO ODURO AKUMFI-AMEYAW**

5 Aldershot Walk Manchester M11 3UQ

0744 994 9031

kojoameyaw@gmail.com

## **Personal Profile**

I am an IT professional with 10 years of educational experience and 6 years of work experience looking to broaden my experience in the industry. I am very optimistic and energetic with a perfectionist attitude that drives me to complete all tasks to the highest possible standard. I have excellent working knowledge of various Windows and Mac OSX software applications as well as Most Computer Security Technologies and can work with limited supervision, as I am self-motivated.

## **Technical Proficiency**

- Security Tools: Aircrak, Wireshark, Metasploit, Burp Suit
- Operating Systems: Windows, Windows Server, Mac OX, Linux (Ubuntu, Kali)
- Network Systems/Monitoring: Active Directory, Apache server, Snort
- Analytic Tools: Google Analytics, MS PowerBi
- VMware
- Cisco ASA Firewall
- Palo alto network firewalls
- Sophos UTM Firewall
- Hack the Box member (Since Feb 2019)
- Encase Forensic Tool
- Autopsy Foresic Tool

## **Professional Qualifications**

Manchester Metropolitan University (September 2018-2019)

# **Msc Cyber Security**

-Selected Modules: Introduction to Computer Forensics and Security (5 Week Encase forensic software training)

Advanced computer networks and Operating systems

Cryptography and Encryption

Advanced network Security

Manchester Metropolitan University, UK (2016-2017)

## **BSC Computer Network Security with Penetration Testing**

- Selected Modules: infrastructure security strategy, penetration testing, negotiated research
- Dissertation: Blockchain technology in mainstream bank transactions.

University of Salford, UK (2014-2016)

#### **Computer Network Security with Ethical Hacking Foundation Degree**

- Selected Modules: Linux Fundamentals, Network fundamentals, Web Security, Server with Client Security, Introduction to Security Concepts, Network Admin & Security, Project management, Securing Remote Access, Firewall Security Technologies
- Cisco CCNA Security Certification (2015)
- PaloAlto Firewall Training (Problem solving practical exam) (8weeks)

The Manchester College, UK (2013-2014)

# IT Incorporating CCENT BTEC Sub Diploma L3

- Selected Modules: Computer Systems, Managing Networks, Computer Networks, Communication
  Technologies, Networked Systems Security
- CCNA Routing and Switching Certificate

The Manchester College, UK (2013)

## Cisco IT Essentials- Pro Diploma L2

- Selected Modules: Customer Support Provision, Install and Configure ICT Equipment and Operating Systems, ICT Repair Centre Procedure, Cisco IT Essentials 1&2, Cisco PC Hardware and Software

The Manchester College, UK (2012)

## ICT System Support - PC Maintenance Diploma Level 1

 Selected Modules: Dismantle, assemble, install and maintain a desktop computing system, Fundamentals of Computing Systems and Customer Care

All Nations University, Ghana (2010)

## **Computer Science Degree**

- Selected Modules: Introduction to computers, Artificial Intelligence, Oracle, Discreet mathematics, Visual Basic programming, Research methodology, Calculus, Java, C and C# programming, System Analysis & Design, Operating Systems, Operations Research, Data Structures, Communication Skills

#### **Work Experience**

Freedom Finance Ltd 6 Months contract (Dec 2017-2018)

## Network Admin and 1st Line support analyst

- First point of contact for 200 users
- Office 365 administration
- Printer service and maintenance (11 Network based printers)
- Server maintenance
- PBX Phone set-up and administration
- Noble Digital dialler application support
- Zoiper digital dialler support
- Sophos UTM firewall Administration and VPN set up
- Server 2012 & 2003 Administration
- Active directory
- Provided 1<sup>st</sup> line support for HMC Funding retail project, liaised with 3<sup>rd</sup> party in providing phone numbers for source codes, and oversaw the configuration of numbers on routing table and linking to our network.
- Provided support to honeycomb finance as network administrator
- Administrator on Harmony call recording platform
- Dell Desktop Authority Administrator
- PRTG Administrator
- DBxtra Administrator
- System and application support for Asda loans Staff
- Dell Power edge rack server administration support and maintenance

The Message Trust, Manchester, UK (2016-2017)

#### 1<sup>st</sup> & 2<sup>nd</sup> Line Support Technician (volunteering)

## Duties:

- support the IT systems administrator: setting up and maintaining user accounts especially for new employees, using both windows Power-shell and active directory.
- system maintenance: undertaking hardware audits around the whole organisation to make sure workstations are in the same state as they were freshly built.
- take requests on Spice-works our IT Helpdesk software and could close between 10 to 15 tickets a day on 1st and second line tasks.
- support in building new computers, this could be between 3 to 5 computers a day on a need basis.
- service network based printers and dealing with employee IT equipment faults which ranged from internet connectivity to hardware failure issues.
- Undertake software installation and server maintenance

Lloyds Banking Group (CITSD), UK (2015-2016)

# 1<sup>st</sup> & 2<sup>nd</sup> Line Support Analyst

#### **Duties:**

- Provided support for internal staff: worked as a part of a large group that supports 139,000 internal staff and fulfilled 10,500 requests per month. We were the support for engineers working on the 20,000 servers maintained across Lloyds banking group, this included the 110,000 desktops and 18,000 virtual desktops.
- had access to several bank mainframes
- resolved faults, undertook password resets, offshore contractor's security tokens.
- Responsible for assigning engineers to specific faults
- Performed computer troubleshooting.

GSM Appliances Ltd, UK (2012-2014)

## **Computer Systems Technician**

#### **Duties:**

- Building computers and making operating system installations on computers and getting it ready for sales, worked on 15 computers a day on average.
- I also performed some sales and customer service tasks.

Vodafone Ltd, Ghana (2010-2011)

# 1st & 2nd Line IT Support

#### **Duties:**

- Understudied network technician to a customer base of over 50,000
- Taking inbound calls and solving internet connectivity problems over the phone.
- I performed numerous tasks for both internal staff and external staff as network technician and IT technician installing new workstations and ensuring internal network and internet connectivity.

## **Hobbies and Interests**

I enjoy playing basketball, and researching topics of interest on the internet. I also enjoy watching movies and solving computer problems for hardware or software applications, or other technical IT problems.

#### References

Dev Lunsford	Paul Ashby	Ernest Edem Edifor
Senior Systems Administrator	Associate Lecturer (Computing)	Senior Lecturer
The Message Trust	The Manchester College	Manchester Met. Uni.
1 Harper Rd, Manchester M22 4RG	Ashton Old Rd, Manchester M11 2WH	Manchester, M15 6BH
dev.lunsford@message.org.uk	pashby@tmc.ac.uk	e.edifor@mmu.ac.uk
0161 946 2324	07866 334 022	0161 247 3800